Islamahad, Pakistan

□ (+92) 331-9503 705 | 💌 aqkhan1247@gmail.com | 🖹 qadeerkhan | 🛅 qadeer-khan-17897982 | 💆 @imqadeerkhan

# Summary.

Current Manager Technology at a leading multi-national company ACE Money Transfer. 6+ years of experience specializing in the backend development, automatons, product scaling, PHP/MySQL, and building digital products. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

# Work Experience

### **ACE Money Transfer**

Manchester, United Kingdom

Manager Technology

July. 2016 - Current

- Implemented Agile Frameworks in Software Team to deliver quality products in Product Owner and Scrum Master roles
- Concept to delivery of digital products by working closely with executives and board members
- Managed and Developed a digital payments platform to process cross-border transactions using PHP-Laravel, MySQL and ReactJS
- Developed a Customer Relation Managment Solution to automate VOIP Calls, Chats and Tickets
- Developed an Anti Money Laundering (AML) and Sanction screening system
- Developed a complete ERP including Business Planning, Human Resource Management and Business Accounting
- Managed hybrid infrastructure (Amazon AWS + Rackspace) utilizing IaC(Infrastructure as Code) tools like Ansible and Terraform.
- · Managed and developed a complete Digital Wallet Project to open a full-fledged UK Bank Account with IBAN
- · System Integration with BAAS and Card Issuers to Launch Mastercard debit cards in UK
- System Integration with 50+ Banks worldwide to support payments in 100+ countries

E4 Technologies. Islamabad, Pakistan

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan. 2016 - June. 2016

- Developed a VET service portal using PHP/Laravel
- Implemented RESTful API server for VET mobile applications
- Built and deployed overall service infrastructure utilizing several AWS stack(Including EC2, ECS, Route 53, S3, CloudFront, RDS, ElastiCache, IAM), focusing on high-availability, fault tolerance, and auto-scaling.

Softtech Media Islamabad, Pakistan

PHP DEVELOPER

June. 2013 - Jan. 2016

- · Worked with various financial institutions to build and manage a remittance management system.
- Developed an API for a football bidding application along with client-server messaging

### Certifications

#### **Cloud Developer | Cloud Computing**

Online

 Cloud computing impacts all careers, and an awareness of the opportunities associated with this emerging field is critical. From backup and storage to PAAS, SAAS, microservices, and web services, this certification covered the essential knowledge and skills I need for a career in cloud development

Agile Project Manager Online

LinkedIn

2021

This certification focus on delivering projects with the highest level of performance and quality as an agile project manager. This certificate helps
me build a solid foundation in leading and motivating agile project teams, from developing user stories and agile charts to driving productive
meetings.

### **Fundamentals of digital marketing**

**BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN ENGINEERING** 

Online

GOOGLE DIGITAL WORKSHOP

2021

• This certification covers the fundamentals of digital marketing to help grow a business online

## **Education**

#### Pakistan Institute of Engineering and Applied Sciences (PIEAS)

Islamabad, Pakistan

Jul. 2012 - Jul. 2016

• CGPA: 3.52